### Heshan Tharindu Kalubowila

91/3, Samupakara WM, Honnathara,
Piliyandala, SriLanka
+94773530119
Heshant3@gmail.com
heshan.dev

# **Career Summary**

I am an Information and Communication Technology (BICT(Hons)) graduate from the Rajarata University of Sri Lanka with over 1 years of experience as a Front-end developer. My passion lies in front-end development, and I constantly seek opportunities to learn and grow in this field. I am driven by my goal of continuously expanding my knowledge and expertise in information technology through hard work and dedication.

# **Work Experience and Responsibilities**

## **Associate UI/UX Engineer**

HELAMID (PVT) LTD, 66, Weliweriya West, Sri Lanka Feb 2022-Present

- Front End Developing a dynamic and interactive website using Reacts, JavaScript, and CSS that ensures high traffic and user experience, resulting in a 60% Increase in sales revenue. (Testing changes/bug fixes to provide the Website function correctly.)
- Front end Developing Learning Management System (LMS) using Reacts that ensured high engagement and user satisfaction. (Testing changes/bug fixes to provide the Website function correctly.)
- UI Designing Using Figma and Illustrator & developing Meal Oder System Web Applications using React, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Maintaining LMS system with over 500 students.
- Implementing website changes and integration scripts to meet clients' needs and SEO requirements.
- Leading the front-end development team.
- I have been involved in and developed more than 10 front-end development projects.
- Debugging QA Errors.

#### **Front End Developer**

*Like Mart, Horana, Sri Lanka* May 2018 – 2021 Feb

- UI/UX Designing and developing Smart IOT base mobile applications using android studio.
- Front end developing Learning Management System (LMS) using React.
- Developing a Front-End bulldozer booking website using React.
- Developing Mini bank management Project for Sri Lanka Dhamma School students using Visual Basic.
- UI/UX Designing a Vegetable shop website using Figma, HTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- Maintaining Learning Management System.
- Developing Innovative Embed System (IOT & Arduino base).
- Developing react online burger shop platform.

### UI/UX Designer & 3D Designer

#### Freelance

September 2019-Present

- UI/UX Designing web and mobile applications using Figma and Adobe XD.
- I have built over seven WordPress websites, including blogs, news, and company websites.
- Realistic 3d modelling and Rendering using Maya, Blender, Solid Works, keyshot, 3d Max.
- Video Editing & Animating.
- Graphic Designing.

### **Education**

Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology (BICT) Honours Degree (2018 - 2023) Rajarata University of Sri Lanka, Mihintale

Final year research project - The human respiratory system for sound analysis and diagnosis detection using a wireless stethoscope with machine learning.

# **Skills Summary**

- Programming languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, ReactJS, Three.js, Vue.js, PHP, jQuery, React Native
- UI Design tools Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch, UXPin, Zeplin
- Web tools WordPress, Shopify, Wix, Bootstrap
- Mobile Application Development Tools Android Studio
- Database Management Tools MySQL, PhpMyAdmin, MongoDB
- Experience in Ubuntu, MacOS, and Windows operating systems
- Sound Interpersonal skills
- Written and Verbal communication skill in English Languages
- Expert In general software applications such as Microsoft Office packages
- Expert In Adobe Creative Suite
- Expert In 3D Modelling software applications such as MAYA, Blender, Solid Works, Keyshot, 3D Max
- Expert in Graphics designing such as Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, CorelDRAW, Sketch
- Inventions were invented for existing problems in Sri Lanka.
- Dynamic Team Player
- Problem solving and debugging

#### **Certifications & Licenses**

- Honor of Invention 3rd International Young Inventors Award Innovation Competition. (2016)
   (World Invention Intellectual Property Associations)
- Gold Prize 3rd International Young Inventors Award Innovation Competition. (2016)
- Grand Winner "Innova minds" Innovation competition (2016)
- Gold Medal ALL Island School Inventors' Competition (2015)
- Silver Medal ALL Island School Inventors' Competition (2017)
- Certificate of participation "Fight Against COVID-19" Project (2020)
- Modern Alcohol Detecting Unit

(LK 2435465755434 Filed Oct 16, 2016) Patents Pending

Fully Automatic Water & Soap Dispenser

(LK/P/21298 Filed Aug 17, 2020) Patents Pending

## Languages

- English
- Sinhala

### Reference

Mr. Isuru Udara
Director, Helamid (PVT)LTD,
66, Weliweriya West,Sri Lanka
support@helamid.com
+94 70 600 2940

Mrs. Dinusha Premasiri
Lecturer, Department of ICT, Faculty of Technology,
Rajarata University of Sri Lanka, Mihintale
dmpremas@tec.rjt.ac.lk
+94 71 357 5231